<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-16T21:02:05-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Brennen’s blog</title><subtitle>Just a place for my occasional ramblings.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Condo Remodel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/16/condo-remodel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Condo Remodel" /><published>2020-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/16/condo-remodel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/16/condo-remodel.html">&lt;h1&gt;Condo remodel&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  About 3 months ago Emily and I bought a condo in the Queen Anne neighborhood of Seattle. It's on the second floor of a 4-story building with 18 units total. Although the unit was in pretty good shape overall, there were a lot of things that hadn't been updated since the building was built in 1985. We didn't like the thin, dark wood baseboards and the big mirrored wall in the dining room. The carpet was pretty old we didn't love the color of the hardwood floors. So over the last few months we've made quite a few changes. We hired a contractor to put in the carpet, but everything else was done ourselves, with the help of a few amazing friends. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Major Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Floors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of having the hardwood flooring abruptly end at both ends of the kitchen we wanted the floor the flow though the entire house, which meant tearing up the exiting hardwood in the kitchen and entryway. That turned out to be a much bigger project than I anticipated, especially in the kitchen where the existing floor ran under the kitchen cabinets. That meant renting a special saw that could cut the floor right at the base of the cabinets. After making the cuts we could replace the floor in the center while leaving the old floor underneath the cabinets. The old floor was also real hardwood, which means it's really heavy. So hauling all of that off was a bit more troublesome than I expected.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Once we tore out the existing baseboards, carpet, and hardwood, we discovered that the subfloor underneath those areas was not at the same level. So before we could lay down laminate flooring we had to put down plywood where the hardwood floor had been to raise it up about 3/8&quot; and match the level of where the carpet was. In addition to that, there were several spots where the subfloor underneath the carpet was not very level, so we had to fill some spots will subfloor patch to get the entire floor as flat as possible.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  After all of the floor prep was finished, laying the new floor went fairly quickly. We were able to finish the entire floor in 2 days over a weekend. We left the existing floor in both bathrooms and the laundry room.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Baseboards and Crown Molding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After laying down the floor we painted, cut, and installed new baseboards in most of the house. We also installed crown molding as well to make the bedrooms and common areas a bit more interesting. This was one of the most time-consuming parts of the whole project just because of how many steps there are: Paint, measure, cut, install, caulk the seams, fill the nail holes, paint over the fill.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Paint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Painting was mostly done before the floor was installed, but like most projects it ended up taking a bit longer than we thought it would. We re-painted most of the walls an off-white and then painted the ceilings in the main room and office blue. For our bedroom we painted the ceiling purple, which I was a bit nervous about but I'm really happy with how it turned out. Almost everyone we talked to about painting the ceiling a dark color said it was a bad idea because it would look out of place or make the room look smaller, but we did it anyway and we're really happy with the results.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mirror Trim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We didn't love the large mirrored wall in the dining room. Part of the reason was because the mirror was actually in 3 separate panels, so there were two big seams that were very distracting. Our solution was to add trim over the top of the mirror to cover the seams and add some dimension. The process was pretty simple, we just cut each trim piece to size and then glued them strait to the mirror with liquid nails. After that dried we filled the seams with mud to make the whole thing look seamless.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Laundry Room&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The laundry room looked like it was originally configured to have the dryer opposite the door and the washer on the left, but at some point the previous owners had installed a tiny stackable washer and dryer instead, both on the left wall. Do make that work they had moved the dryer electrical outlet to the other wall and ran the dryer vent across the floor and over the water heater, which was really ugly. I had to move the dryer outlet back to its original location and take out the venting. Even the original configuration wasn't quite large enough to fit the washer and dryer we wanted though, so we ended up moving the cabinets all the way up to the ceiling and changing the door to swing out instead of in to make room. In the future we might also replace the water header with a tankless water heater, which would allow the washer and dryer to fit side by side against the left wall.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Smaller Changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of smaller things we did along the way that I wanted to mention as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced light fixtures in the dining room and laundry room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced most of the light switches with smart switches&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changed the look of the fireplace using stick-on vinyll for the tiles and a grout pen for the grout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced all of the gold/brass door-knobs and hinges with brushed nickel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced a few of the dated-looking thermostats and smoke alarms with new ones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced the sliding doors in the entryway with bifold doors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Condo remodel About 3 months ago Emily and I bought a condo in the Queen Anne neighborhood of Seattle. It's on the second floor of a 4-story building with 18 units total. Although the unit was in pretty good shape overall, there were a lot of things that hadn't been updated since the building was built in 1985. We didn't like the thin, dark wood baseboards and the big mirrored wall in the dining room. The carpet was pretty old we didn't love the color of the hardwood floors. So over the last few months we've made quite a few changes. We hired a contractor to put in the carpet, but everything else was done ourselves, with the help of a few amazing friends.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rantings of a 23-year-old liberal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/rantings-of-a-23-year-old-liberal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rantings of a 23-year-old liberal" /><published>2020-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/rantings-of-a-23-year-old-liberal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/08/rantings-of-a-23-year-old-liberal.html">&lt;h1&gt;Rantings of a 23-year-old liberal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I’m disappointed. I’m disappointed that 70 million Americans think Donald Trump is doing a good job as our president. Sure, Joe Biden won, and I’m very happy about that, but this race should not have even been close. I know all politicians lie and make promises that they can’t keep, but Trump took that to new extremes and no even cares. People have become so indoctrinated by fox news to think anything even slightly left-leaning is complete evil that they will support literally anyone else. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

    And it’s ironic, because so many republican voters are voting against their own interests. They insist that Obamacare and food stamps and all the other social safety net programs should be repealed because they cost too much tax payer money. But you know who benefits from those programs the most? Republicans, because they tend to be less educated and therefore less wealthy than democrats. And the claim about it costing too much tax payer money doesn’t make much sense either, because the majority of those tax dollars come from big cities because that’s where all the high paying jobs are. And you know who is paying those big city taxes? Democrats.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    But no amount of logic can sway a republican voter, because anything you bring up is countered with a simple “I don’t want to pay taxes because taxes are stealing and that restricts my freedom”. They don’t care that without taxes they wouldn’t have roads, or clean drinking water, or public parks, or food safety standards, or healthcare (because good luck paying for private healthcare if you don’t have a college degree and are working a low-paying job, as so many republicans are). To them, none of those things can compete with “true freedom”, even if that freedom means they have a much lower standard of living.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    One of the great ironies is that many people will gladly pay 10% tithing to a church that already has 100 billion dollars stashed away with no oversight or transparency on how that money is used, but when the government asks for a similar amount, all to be spent for very specific things that we have agreed on as a democracy, that’s somehow communism and can be compared to being treated like a zoo animal.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I get that there is concern over government waste. That’s a valid concern. But nobody ever talks about private sector waste. Look at instances of government projects being subbed out to private companies, and the results are almost always riddled with cost overruns and missed deadlines. Sure, the government screws up sometimes but that’s to be expected. Everyone screws up sometimes. And much of what the government is trying to do is unprecedented. Take public education as an example. It gets crap all the time for being poorly run and ineffective, but it’s a relatively new thing to try and educate an entire population. There are bound to be mistakes. And is going back to the days when most people couldn’t even read really a better alternative than fixing our education system? There are bound to be problems, but I think allocating the proper resources to let our education system fix those problems is a better solution that just saying “Public education isn’t working as well as I want it to so let’s stop giving them money”.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I’m sad that half of America is so ignorant. And I’m sad that religion gets so tied up in politics, because religion teaches you that it’s okay to be ignorant and that you shouldn’t question too much. So then that bleeds over into politics where if people could just think for themselves, a lot of them would conclude that the republican platform doesn’t make any sense. But instead they are taught that they should only listen to fox news and other people on “their team”, because anyone with contradictory information is obviously just part of some selfish scheme. It’s hard not to draw a direct connection back to christianity that preaches scientific evidence should always be second to the Bible and the teachings of church leaders, even if they objectively make way less sense than the scientific explanations for things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I often get told as an atheist to just leave religion alone and let them believe what they want to believe. That’s very hard to do though when religion is actively influencing how people vote and how people treat each other. And when your religion starts getting in the way of sensible politics, I have a problem with that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    A part of my brain says that I should’t even care about politics. After all, I work for a big tech company that pays me lots of money, and I have several years of experience in one of the fastest-growing, highest-paying industries there is. I shouldn’t personally care if republicans want to completely destroy our social safety net, I doubt I will ever need to use those programs personally (although I have used them in the past and they’ve been great). Republicans don’t seem to have any problem not-caring about immigrants and poor people, so why should I care? But I can’t be that heartless. I know republicans don’t see it as being heartless, but I don’t know how else you can spin it when you actively vote for policies and politicians that hurt the poor, the disabled, the old, and minorities. I don’t understand how they can support such restrictive immigration policies that prevent good people from escaping poverty and oppression in their home countries.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I had a lot of hope before this election that Trump’s base isn’t as big as it used to be, and that we would easily win the presidency and the senate. Then we could start making some real change that would help all Americans, even the low-income conservatives who don’t understand how much they could personally benefit from universal healthcare and other increased government spending. But with the changes of democrats winning the Senate looking pretty slim (though I’m still hopeful Georgia will surprise us), I’m left not really knowing how to feel. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I just remembered the mis-management if COVID-19 is a whole other thing that I could spend a few paragraphs taking about, but I’m tired so I won’t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    So in conclusion, I’m sad, angry, and confused. I’m sad that so many people are struggling who wouldn’t have to if the government served its intended purpose of helping the people. I’m angry that there’s nothing I can do to because I’m so outnumbered (I will probably donate to the senate campaigns in Georgia, but that seems almost meaningless). And I’m confused how so many people, many of whom I can personally attest are kind, intelligent people, can be so brainwashed by religion and conservative news that they support policies and politicians that actively harm millions of people. I’m exhausted and I don’t feel like I can make much of a difference, but I also feel like these are such important things that I can’t just stop thinking about it and stop talking about it.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Rantings of a 23-year-old liberal I’m disappointed. I’m disappointed that 70 million Americans think Donald Trump is doing a good job as our president. Sure, Joe Biden won, and I’m very happy about that, but this race should not have even been close. I know all politicians lie and make promises that they can’t keep, but Trump took that to new extremes and no even cares. People have become so indoctrinated by fox news to think anything even slightly left-leaning is complete evil that they will support literally anyone else.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Loss of Faith</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/27/my-loss-of-faith.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Loss of Faith" /><published>2017-11-27T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/27/my-loss-of-faith</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/11/27/my-loss-of-faith.html">&lt;h1&gt;My Loss of Faith&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/joseph-smith.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px; display: inline-block; float: right; margin: 15px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was raised in the LDS church and was an active member for my whole childhood. When I was 18 I moved to Albuquerque and started college, and for a few months I continued to attend church and institute classes, but it wasn’t the same as it was in Farmington. It all just felt like a waste of time, so I stopped going. I was doing well in school, was happily married, and didn’t feel like I needed the church. I never doubted the gospel and I always figured I would go back to church at some point, but as I spent more and more time away from the church I started to have a lot of questions. I was happier than ever without the gospel in my life, so I finally considered the possibility that the teachings of the LDS church aren’t true. As I searched for answers I found tons of stuff that you don’t ever learn about in church, parts of its history that the church intentionally leaves out because it would cause people to question the truth of it all. One great source of information is &lt;a href=&quot;https://cesletter.org/Letter-to-a-CES-Director.pdf&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The CES Letter&lt;/a&gt;, which outlines a lot of early church history from an external perspective. As I tried to justify all of the contradictions, there came a point when I could no longer ignore the huge amount of evidence against the church. This is by no means a comprehensive list, but what follows are the most significant issues that led me to leave the LDS church.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Divinity of the Book of Mormon&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;View of the Hebrews&lt;/i&gt; is a book written by Ethan Smith in 1823, 7 years before the Book of Mormon. The book has many similarities to the Book of Mormon, including the theory that Native Americans are descendants of the Israelites.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Some other ideas found in both books are the destruction of Jerusalem, the scattering of Israel, the restoration of the Ten Tribes, Hebrews leaving the old world for the new world, and a Breastplate and Urim &amp;amp; Thummim. Ethan Smith was a pastor for five years in Poultney, Vermont where Oliver Cowdery lived until he was 20,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; so it’s very possible that Oliver attended his sermons and read or had a copy of &lt;i&gt;View of the Hebrews&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;The Late War&lt;/i&gt; was a book published in 1816 in New York about the war of 1812.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It was used in schools around the country and Joseph Smith likely used it in school. It is written in a scriptural style and contains lots of verses that are almost identical to those in the Book of Mormon. Here are just a few examples:&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s4&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Late War&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Book of Mormon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      the land ... most plentiful ... yielding gold and silver, and ... all manner of creatures which are used for food, And ... the huge mammoth that once moved on the borders ... It is more wonderful than the elephant;&lt;br&gt;(20:11-16)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      the land, ... exceeding rich, ... of gold, and of silver, and ... all manner of ... animals which were useful for the food of man. And ... cureloms and cumoms; ... and moreespecially the elephants&lt;br&gt;(Ether 9:17-19)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      near Moravian Town ... And it came to pass ... the army ... were under ... a chief warrior, whom they called Tecumseh [...] smote their chief warrior [Tecumseh],  and slew him ... he fell to the earth.&lt;br&gt;(27-28)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      people of Morianton ... And it came to pass ... the army ... was led by a man whose name was Teancum [...] they did pursue Teancum, and slew him ... he was dead, and had gone the way of all the earth.&lt;br&gt;(Alma 50:33,35, Alma 62:36-37)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      two thousand hardy men, who ... fought freely for their country ... Now the men of war ... were ... men of dauntless courage.&lt;br&gt;(25:5-6)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      two thousand of those young men ... to defend their country. ... they took their weapons of war, ... were all young men, and they were exceeding valiant for courage&lt;br&gt;(Alma 53:18-20)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      [men] were prepared ... and they let loose their weapons of war ... and smote ... with great slaughter. And the deep ditch that surrounded the fort was strewed with their slain and their wounded.&lt;br&gt;(29:20-23)
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      [men] were prepared, with their swords and their slings, to smite ... with an immense slaughter ... ditches ...filled up in a measure with their dead and wounded.&lt;br&gt;(Alma 49:20-25)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  These examples only begin to show the parallels between the books, and these weren’t the only possible sources. Many other 19th century books, like &lt;i&gt;The First Book of Napoleon&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;The Pirate Hunter&lt;/i&gt; also have striking similarities to the Book of Mormon.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A common argument I hear in support of the Book of Mormon is that Joseph smith had very little formal education, so he couldn’t have possibly written such an elaborate book. Although it’s true that Joseph didn’t have &lt;i&gt;much&lt;/i&gt; formal education, he did have some and he was clearly intelligent enough to read and understand the Bible and many other books. There were also thousands of grammatical mistakes in the original version of the Book of Mormon that have since been changed. Combine that with all of the books containing the same stories as the Book of Mormon and it seems completely reasonable that Joseph smith wrote the entire book himself.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Gold Plates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The church teaches that Joseph Smith used the Urim and Thummim, given to him by Moroni, to look at the plates and translate the characters on them. David Whitmer Emma Smith later said that he only used these while translating the first 116 pages that were later lost, and that when he started translating again he used a seer stone in a hat&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s5&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (a stone which he had also used to search for buried treasure&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s6&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) to translate the rest of the book. The plates were not actually used and often weren’t even in the same room while Joseph was translating. If he didn’t need the plates, why did the Book of Mormon prophets go through all the trouble of engraving them and hauling them around?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Joseph smith said the gold plates weighed 40 to 60 pounds, and were about 6 inches wide, 8 inches long, and 4 inches thick. If they were actually that size and made of gold, they would weigh over 130 pounds and be pretty difficult to move around.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  No one ever saw the gold plates. Even the 3 and 8 witnesses, if you look at all of their individual accounts, claim to have seen them in a vision or with “spiritual eyes”.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We also don’t have original documents or signatures for either of the testimonies, so over the years the church leaders could have reworded it any way they like and then put everyone's names at the bottom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Spirit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Members of the church are told to rely on the Holy Spirit as a witness that the church and it’s teachings are true, but if this is our only form of communication with God, why is it so unreliable? There are many religions around the world with millions of members claiming that they know their church is true because they have felt the spirit. If everyone must eventually come to the LDS church to be saved, why would God send so many mixed messages? Even within the church the spirit can’t seem to testify of the same truth to everyone. A great example is the period of time after Joseph Smith died. For about 6 months after his death, no one knew who the next prophet was supposed to be. Although Brigham Young eventually assumed the role of Prophet, many others gained a following as well, which is why there have been so many branches of the Mormon church. The most notable of these was James Strang, who convinced 4 of the 11 Witnesses as well as 3 other apostles that he should be Joseph’s successor.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; If some of the most righteous men in the church couldn’t tell what the spirit was telling them, how are we expected to know?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Gift of Translation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Many manuscripts were found from Joseph Smith’s scribes containing Egyptian characters with translations. None of these translations are accurate based on our current knowledge of Egyptian. The facsimiles that accompany the book of Abraham have been analyzed by Egyptologists and the translations Joseph Smith gave are completely wrong; none of the scrolls or glyphs we have access to have anything to do with Abraham.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s9&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  According to journal entries by William Clayton, an early church leader, Joseph also claimed to have translated the Kinderhook plates. These were later proven to be fake, at which time the church changed its position and now denies that he ever translated them.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s10&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Out of all the translations Joseph Smith attempted, the two we still have original sources for have both been proven false. How are we then supposed to trust his translation of a set of gold plates that nobody has ever seen?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Temple Ceremonies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Temple ceremonies have changed drastically over the lifetime of the church. That fact alone raises all sorts of questions about a church that claims to be unchanging. Many of the early church leaders, including Joseph Smith Sr., Joseph Smith, and Brigham Young, were Masons. Less than two months after Joseph’s Masonic Initiation he introduced the endowment ceremony in the temple, which was almost identical to the Freemasonic ceremony. They share similar words, handshakes, and clothing, and meaning. Over the years prophets have had many contradicting explanations for the similarities.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s11&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Polygamy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lds.org/scriptures/dc-testament/dc/132?lang=eng#p63&quot;&gt;the Doctrine &amp;amp; Covenants 132:63&lt;/a&gt;, polygamy is only allowed if the woman is a virgin. Many of the women Joseph Smith Married were already married to other men.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Many of them were also children, at least one of them as young as 14.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s12&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; D&amp;amp;C also notes that you must ask your first wife before taking on more wives, but many of Joseph’s marriages were unknown to Emma.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#s13&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Word of Wisdom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Many people believe the Word of Wisdom was a great revelation containing new ideas about health, but the truth is most of it was based on trends from the time it was written. It is also presented in modern times with a completely different meaning than what was originally intended. When the Word of Wisdom was published in 1833, the American Temperance Society was becoming very popular. It advocated that alcohol was immoral, but didn’t say anything about the health effects. Modern studies have shown that red wine actually has numerous health benefits. The Word of Wisdom also doesn’t have anything in it saying you can't have alcoholic drinks, only that you shouldn't drink hard liquor, so why does the church interpret that as meaning you can’t drink wine and beer? Tobacco is the same way, the word of wisdom says not to put it in your belly, but it doesn’t say you can’t smoke it. During Smith’s time doctors would often have their patients eat tobacco as medicine, which people then discovered did more harm than good, hence the strange wording about your belly. And finally, the hot drinks. One possible influence was a popular medical book that stated “an excess of hot drinks caused the blood and insides to heat up and that excess of heat is the most common cause of sickness and death.” So it’s possible that “hot drinks” was literally just referring to temperature. It's quite a stretch to say that hot drinks applies to tea and coffee (and iced tea and coffee) but not to hot cocoa or soup.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts on The LDS Church&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One common respose I hear from members of the church when I bring up these issues is that if you are looking for proof that the church is wrong, you are going to find it; you have to have faith and seek answers with the intent to believe. In response I will say this: I was part of the church for the first 18 years of my life. I read The Book of Mormon cover to cover with the intent to believe that it was true. I felt the spirit occasionally, but it's the same spirit I feel now just living my life. It's really not the spirit at all, it's just hapiness and motiviation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In all aspects of my life I try to keep an open mind and form opinions based on all of the information available, not just the side I want to be correct. Religion is no exception, and there came a point where I just couldn't keep ignoring the mounds of evidence against the church.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;So What Do I Believe?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I believe in kindness and hard work. I believe that this life is the only one we have, so we should make the most of it. Likewise I believe that we should do everything we can to help the people around us, not just accept that they will be made whole in some future life. I believe that great things come from hard work, not from God, and I believe that humans gradually evolved the same way every other species has without any divine help. I believe that there may be some greater force in the universe, but I don't think that force cares much about us. Ultimately, whether there is or isn't a God, it shouldn't affect how we act. We should be good people for the sake of being good people, not because we are afraid of what will happen after we die.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;-Brennen Berkley&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
(I recognize that most of these are from wikipedia which &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; be unreliable, but they are much easier to understand and reference all of the primary sources if you are interested in reading those)
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s1&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/View_of_the_Hebrews&quot;&gt;1. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/View_of_the_Hebrews&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s2&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethan_Smith_(clergyman)&quot;&gt;2. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethan_Smith_(clergyman)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s3&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Late_War_between_the_United_States_and_Great_Britain&quot;&gt;3. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Late_War_between_the_United_States_and_Great_Britain&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s4&quot; href=&quot;https://wordtreefoundation.github.io/thelatewar/&quot;&gt;4. https://wordtreefoundation.github.io/thelatewar/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s5&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lds.org/ensign/1993/07/a-treasured-testament#p13&quot;&gt;5. https://www.lds.org/ensign/1993/07/a-treasured-testament&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s6&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seer_stone_(Latter_Day_Saints)&quot;&gt;6. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seer_stone_(Latter_Day_Saints)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;s7&quot;&gt;7. History of the Church, vol.1, pp.54–55&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s8&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Jesus_Christ_of_Latter_Day_Saints_(Strangite)&quot;&gt;8. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_Jesus_Christ_of_Latter_Day_Saints_(Strangite)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s9&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lds.org/topics/translation-and-historicity-of-the-book-of-abraham&quot;&gt;9. https://www.lds.org/topics/translation-and-historicity-of-the-book-of-abraham&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s10&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinderhook_plates&quot;&gt;10. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinderhook_plates&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s11&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mormonism_and_Freemasonry&quot;&gt;11. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mormonism_and_Freemasonry&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s12&quot; href=&quot;https://www.lds.org/topics/plural-marriage-in-kirtland-and-nauvoo&quot;&gt;12. https://www.lds.org/topics/plural-marriage-in-kirtland-and-nauvoo?lang&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a id=&quot;s13&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Joseph_Smith%27s_wives&quot;&gt;13. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Joseph_Smith%27s_wives&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My Loss of Faith I was raised in the LDS church and was an active member for my whole childhood. When I was 18 I moved to Albuquerque and started college, and for a few months I continued to attend church and institute classes, but it wasn’t the same as it was in Farmington. It all just felt like a waste of time, so I stopped going. I was doing well in school, was happily married, and didn’t feel like I needed the church. I never doubted the gospel and I always figured I would go back to church at some point, but as I spent more and more time away from the church I started to have a lot of questions. I was happier than ever without the gospel in my life, so I finally considered the possibility that the teachings of the LDS church aren’t true. As I searched for answers I found tons of stuff that you don’t ever learn about in church, parts of its history that the church intentionally leaves out because it would cause people to question the truth of it all. One great source of information is The CES Letter, which outlines a lot of early church history from an external perspective. As I tried to justify all of the contradictions, there came a point when I could no longer ignore the huge amount of evidence against the church. This is by no means a comprehensive list, but what follows are the most significant issues that led me to leave the LDS church.</summary></entry></feed>